Guide to the Cornell Wordsworth and Cornell Yeats editorial records, 1974-2011.
Cornell Wordsworth and Cornell Yeats editorial records
- Yeats files
  - CDs and DVDs
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, April 18, 2006; 1988 (Box 8)
      Images for volume: Berg - typescript; To-Day
      ID#: D0076.2
    - Resurrection, The, April 18, 2006; 1989 (Box 8)
      Images for volume: Berg; copy 2
      ID#: D0077.1
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, April 18, 2006; 1989 (Box 8)
      Images for volume: Berg - typescript; To-Day; copy 2
      ID#: D0077.2
    - Resurrection, The, December 7, 2007; 1990 (Box 8)
      Transcriptions of mss
      Creator of media: Selina Guinness
      ID#: D0078
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, June 27, 2008; 1991 (Box 8)
      Images from various NLI MSS
      Creator of media: NLI
      ID#: D0079
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, n.d.; 1992 (Box 8)
      ID#: D0080
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, April 17, 2009; 1993 (Box 8)
      Images from NLI: 8773(4); 8773(5); 8773(23)
      ID#: D0081
    - Unicorn of the Stars and Where there is Nothing, April 17, 2009; 1994 (Box 8)
      Images from NLI: 8777(1); 30,445; 30,595; 29,557; 40,567/83
      Editor name: Wim Van-Mierlo
      ID#: D0082.1
    - On Baile’s Strand
      Images from NLI 30,331
      Creator of media: Jared Curtis & Declan Kiely
      ID#: D0082.2
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 1995 (Box 8)
      Add Mss. 55585. Proof pages of Edition de Luxe, Macmillan
      Editor name: Jared Curtis & Selina Guinness
      ID#: D0083.1
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, n.d.; 1995 (Box 8)
      ID#: D0083.2
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 1996 (Box 8)
      NLI 8766(2), 17v, 21v, missing from original set of scans
      ID#: D0084
    - At The Hawk's Well and The Cat And The Moon, n.d.; 1997 (Box 8)
      PDF of Cornell volume
      Creator of media: Curtis
      ID#: D0085
    - King’s Threshold, The & On Baile’s Strand, n.d.; 1998 (Box 8)
      Archive of unedited images for these two plays
      Editor name: Jared Curtis & Declan Kiely
      ID#: D0086
    - Yeats MS collection and guides, April 17, 2013; 1999 (Box 8)
      Archive of various collections and guides to collections
      ID#: D0087
    - Golden Helmet, The, and The Green Helmet, n.d.; 2000 (Box 8)
      ID#: D0088
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 2001 (Box 8)
      Master InDesign files and final PDF
      ID#: D0089.1
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 2002 (Box 8)
      Images for volume: various
      ID#: D0089.2
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 2003 (Box 8)
      Raw images for volume. Folder 1
      ID#: D0089.3
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 2004 (Box 8)
      Raw images for volume. Folder 2
      ID#: D0089.4
    - Resurrection, The, n.d.; 2005 (Box 8)
      Raw images for volume. Folder 3
      ID#: D0089.5
    - Unicorn of the Stars and Where there is Nothing, n.d.; 2006 (Box 8)
      Master InDesign files and final PDF; images used in book
      ID#: D0090.1
    - Unicorn of the Stars and Where there is Nothing, n.d.; 2007 (Box 8)
      ID#: D0090.2
    - Unicorn of the Stars and Where there is Nothing, n.d.; 2008 (Box 8)
      ID#: D0090.3
    - On Baile's Strand, n.d.; 2009 (Box 8)
      Raw images for volume: Various
      Editor name: Curtis & Kiely
      ID#: D0091.1
    - On Baile's Strand
      ID#: D0091.2
  - Microfilm
    - Yeats Mss (Box 5)
      Reel #5, of Michael Yeats’s ms collection of WBY’s papers
      ID#: M0001
    - Yeats Proofs (Box 5)
      Add Mss 55877, 55890, 55891, 55892. Various proofs from Macmillan Archive
      ID#: M0002
    - Yeats Proofs (Box 5)
      Add Mss 55879. Collected Plays proofs from Macmillan Archive
      ID#: M0003
    - Yeats Mss (Box 5)
      Reel #2, of Michael Yeats’s ms collection of WBY’s papers
      ID#: M0004
    - Yeats Mss (Box 5)
      Reel #3, of Michael Yeats’s ms collection of WBY’s papers
      ID#: M0005
    - Sophocles’ Oedipus at Colonus, May 8, 2003 (Box 5)
      HRC, of typescript of play
      ID#: M0006
    - Deirdre (Box 5)
      NLI 8760(2) & (3) with King’s Threshold NLI 21,505
      ID#: M0007.1
    - King’s Threshold, The (Box 5)
      NLI 21,505; with NLI 8760(2) & (3) of Deirdre
      ID#: M0007.2
    - Sophocles’ Oedipus at Colonus (Box 5)
      NLI 8767(1) & (2)
      ID#: M0008
    - Deirdre (Box 5)
      includes mss of Deirdre, On Baille’s Strand, and The King’s Threshold
      ID#: M0009.1
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 5)
      ID#: M0009.2
    - King’s Threshold, The (Box 5)
      ID#: M0009.3
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 5)
      includes mss of On Baille’s Strand, and The King’s Threshold
      ID#: M0010.1
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 5)
      ID#: M0010.2
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 5)
      British Library LCP 1903/7
      ID#: M0011
    - At the Hawk’s Well and The Cat and the Moon, April 15, 2008 (Box 5)
      NYPL (Berg) “The Well of Immortality”
      ID#: M0012
    - Only Jealousy of Emer, The, and Fighting the Waves (Box 5)
      NLI 8774(1) - (28)
      ID#: M0013
    - Only Jealousy of Emer, The, and Fighting the Waves, March 12, 2000 (Box 5)
      NLI 21,494; NLI 20,873
      ID#: M0014
    - Only Jealousy of Emer, The, and Fighting the Waves (Box 5)
      Houghton Library MS Eng 338.7
      ID#: M0015
    - Diarmuid and Grania (Box 5)
      ID#: M0016
    - Collaborative One-Act Plays, 1901-1903 (Box 5)
      NLI 10,950(3) & NLI 10,950(1)
      ID#: M0017
    - King’s Threshold, The, January 1, 2001 (Box 5)
      NYPL (Berg)
      ID#: M0018
    - Land of Heart’s Desire, The (Box 5)
      Add 53544 (LCP); fair copy, corrected.
      ID#: M0019
    - King’s Threshold, The (Box 5)
      LCP 1903/230 (Add 65665)
      ID#: M0020
    - King’s Threshold, The (Box 5)
      Harvard Library MS 338.3
      ID#: M0021.1
    - On Baille’s Strand, November 20, 2001 (Box 5)
      NYPL (Berg) *22-37788
      ID#: M0021.2
    - (Box 5)
      NYPL (Berg) *ZZ-33745
      ID#: M0022
    - (Box 5)
      NYPL (Berg) *ZZ-33449
      ID#: M0023
    - Samhain (D+G) No.1, copy 1 (Box 5)
      NYPL MNN: *ZZ-37865
      ID#: M0024
    - Sophocles’ Oedipus at Colonus (Box 5)
      NLI 21, 495 & NLI 21, 496(1) + (2)
      ID#: M0025
    - Miscellaneous Yeats mss (Box 9)
      Images of NLI mss obtained by Clark betw. 1950s and 1985
      Creator of media: Clark
      ID#: M0026
    - White Vellum Notebook and other Yeats mss (Box 9)
      Photographed later than Harvard reels (WVNb is paginated here); now NLI
      ID#: M0027
    - Yeats plays: Deirdre, The Helmet, Shadowy Waters, Hour Glass, Player Queen (Box 9)
      Images of mss then belonging to Michael Yeats, now in NL
      ID#: M0028
  - Prints
    - NLI Manuscript 13,582 (Rapallo Notebook #5) (Box 6)
      Drafts of various Yeats works: Words Upon the Window Pane; Resurrection, etc.
      Creator of media: NLI via SUNY SB
      ID#: P0001
    - New Poems, July 21, 1999 (Box 6)
      Various photos and photocopies for Appendix IV of New Poems (q.v.)
      Creator of media: Various
      ID#: P0002
    - New Poems (Oversized), July 21, 1999 (Box 7)
    - King’s Threshold, The (Box 6)
      Photos of actors on stage
      ID#: P0003
    - King of the Great Clock Tower, The, and a Full Moon in March (Box 6)
      Photos and photocopies for the volume from various sources
      ID#: P0004
    - King of the Great Clock Tower, The, and a Full Moon in March (Oversize) (Box 7)
    - King of the Great Clock Tower, The, and a Full Moon in March (Box 6)
      ID#: P0005
    - King of the Great Clock Tower, The, and a Full Moon in March (Oversize) (Box 7)
    - King of the Great Clock Tower, The, and a Full Moon in March (Box 6)
      ID#: P0006
    - King of the Great Clock Tower, The, and a Full Moon in March (Oversize) (Box 7)
    - Collaborative One-Act Plays, 1901-1903, November 15, 2002 (Box 6)
      Creator of media: James Pethica
      ID#: P0007
    - On Baille’s Strand, August 28, 2001 (Box 6)
      Photos of sketches of stage plans for On Baille's Stand and The King's Threshold from NLI
      ID#: P0008
    - On Baille’s Strand, October 15, 2010 (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, Berg A-H
      ID#: P0009
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, brit. libr. LCP
      ID#: P0010
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, add MS 55879 brit. libr.
      ID#: P0012
    - On Baille’s Strand, February 4, 2009 (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, BL LCP 1903, add MS 65649 OBS
      ID#: ?
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, add MS 55887 & 55890 brit. libr.
      ID#: P0013
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, Harvard GMS Thr 32, Houghton Library
      ID#: P0014
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, music for OBS by Herbert Hughes, NLI (via Stony Brook U.)
      ID#: P0015
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 8760 (8, 14, 18)
      ID#: P0016
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 21,498
      ID#: P0017
    - On Baille’s Strand, October 15, 2010 (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 29,552 (1, 2, 3)
      ID#: P0018
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30017
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30,032
      ID#: P0019
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30,329
      ID#: P0020
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30,331
      ID#: P0021
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30,384 2r, 3r
      ID#: P0022
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30,384 1r (NLI 30,403)
      ID#: P0023
    - On Baille’s Strand (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NLI 30,475
      ID#: P0024
    - Where There Is Nothing (Box 10)
      Photocopies for the volume from various sources, NYPL ms. dept, typescripts A-D
      ID#: P0025
  - Other files
    - Cornell Yeats: Funding, 2000-2006 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Cornell Yeats: Editors' correspondence, 1999-2005 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Galley proofs of "On Bailes' Strand", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)